# Anshul Sonpure

# Associate Staff Engineer

🛮 anshul.sonpure@outlook.com 📞 9827118513 🏲 https://anshul-sonpure.github.io/Anshul\_Sonpure



### Professional Experience

#### Associate Software Engineer, Nagarro

2022 - present

Working on Energy Trading Application. Involved in Functional as well as Automation testing. Technologies used: C#, Coded UI, .net framework.

#### Software Test Engineer, Amdocs, India

2021 - 2022

Worked on ULM and SLM application.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Worked on API Testing, focusing on test case creation and automation suite maintenance.
- · Automated the Manual test cases using ReadyAPI and Postman.
- Validation of JSON request-response and assertions. Technologies used: API Testing, ReadyAPI, Kibana, AWS micorservices, SQL and Postman.

#### Programmer Analyst,

Cognizant Technologies Solution

2019 - 2021

Worked as Functional and Automation QA:

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Involved in the implementation of the Test Automation Framework build using UFT and TOSCA.
- Demonstrated Web Automation and API testing via Rest Assured and Selenium for better execution time and better reporting.
- Developed Test Frameworks in Selenium for UI Regression Test Automation and when necessary, and potentially execute Unit Test Automation (Java /TestNG).
- Worked on shell script testing and execution and SQL Technologies used: Manual, Automation testing, UFT, TOSCA, Rest Assured, Selenium, TestNG, and Cucumber.

### Information Security Consultant,

ABP Holding

2017 - 2018

Worked as Team Lead

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Involved in investigating security breaches and other cybersecurity incidents.
- Monitoring and restricting access to sensitive, confidential, or other high-security data.

### About Me

I'am an Enthusiastic engineer who ispassionate about Automation and QualityAssurance, and also who is keen on IT andanything about it. My expertise is in Web-UI Automation, API Testing, and Web-Security Testing. I'm looking forward tocollaborate on Test AutomationFrameworks Development (Web, Mobileand API).



#### Skills

#### **Web Automation**

Selenium, TestNG, Cucumber, Maven

#### **API Testing**

Rest Assured, Karate Framework, Cucumber

#### **Web Security Testing**

**OWASP Vulnerabilities** 

#### **Programming Languages**

Java, Python, Shell Script

#### **Code Management**

Git, Github, Bitbucket



#### Education

**M.Tech**, NRI-Institute of Research and Technology

2013 - 2016

#### Bachelor of Engineering,

NRI-Institute of Research and Technology

2009 - 2013

- Performed application and infrastructure penetration tests, as well as physical security review and social engineering tests for our global clients.
- Provided KT to the Development team for a better understanding of Vulnerabilities.
- Coordinated with the dev team to ensure the closure of reported vulnerabilities by explaining the ease of exploitation and the impact of the issue.

On-Site Experience: Qatar (as Project Coordinator)

#### **Software Tester**, *HariOm Technologies*

2016 - 2016

Worked as Functional Tester Roles and Responsibilities:

- Performed Business functionality testing, which involved testing of all core functions of the application.
- Executed manual and automated regression test cases after the bug fixes as per test scenarios.
- Performed Database testing using SQL queries.



Leadership | Detail-oriented | Multitasking Adaptability | Presentation skills | Project management | Keen-Learner

## Declaration

All the information shared in the resume is correct, and I take full responsibility for its correctness.

Anshul Sonpure IO/O2/2O23



#### Scrum and Agile

Udemy - June'2020

# Advanced Selenium Webdriver with Java and TestNG

Udemy - September'2020

# Java: Automated API Testing with REST Assured

Linked Learning –Jan 04'2022



#### **Web Automation Framework**

Selenium Java-based Web UI Automation Framework implementing Extent report and Page Object Model.

#### **API Testing using Rest Assured**

GitHub repo for beginners and learners. It offers comprehensive tutorials and resources to make learning rest assured easy.

#### **API Testing using Karate Framework**

Repository for learning Karate Framework for API Testing.

### Login based Application

 $Implementation \ of \ the \ backend (Node.js) \ routes \ with \ the \ front end (EJS-based \ template).$